U.S. Emergency Board No. 133 Exhibits 5054
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board No. 133 Exhibits
1960
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board
5054
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Maps, photographs.
Collection consists of carrier exhibits and New York Harbor Carriers' Conference Committee vs. Railroad Marine Harber Council: exhibits.
3337339
Biographical / Historical
U.S. Emergency Board No. 133 was appointed in 1960 to settle a dispute between certain carriers represented by the New York Harbor Carriers' Conference Committee and labor organizations which were members of the Railroad Marine Harbor Council.
The dispute began with various labor unions proposing changes in and additions to existing agreements under Section 6 of the Railway Labor Act. The unions took the position that they should not be compared to or treated as railroad employees but should have the same consideration as seamen. This was rejected by the Board.
The Board also dealt with the substance of the demands regarding wages, welfare benefits, and improved holiday and vacation benefits. It recommended a two percent base increase, elimination of the cost-of-living escalator, broadened the category of employee eligible for holiday pay, and provided for a sixty day notice regarding the elimination of a position.
Scope and Contents
Consist of carrier exhibits.
The exhibits deal with general wage increases (1937-1960) for railroad non-operating employees and railroad marine employees; general wage increases (1939-1960); retirement, and unemployment and sickness benefits in the railroad industry.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 10, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Mediation and conciliation, Industrial -- United States -- Cases; Railroads -- Employees; Arbitration, Industrial -- Train ferries -- New York (State) -- New York; Employee fringe benefits -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Mediation and conciliation, Industrial -- Railroads -- United States; Mediation and conciliation, Industrial -- Train ferries -- New York (State) -- New York; New York Harbor (N.Y. and N.J.); Wages -- Mediation and conciliation, Industrial -- United States; Wages -- Merchant marine -- United States; Wages -- Railroads -- United States; New York Harbor Carriers' Conference; New York (State). Board of Mediation and Arbitration; Railroad Marine Harbor Council (New York, N.Y.); United States. Emergency Board No. 133
3337339
- Railroads' Exhibit No. 2. Railroad Floating Equipment., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Contains nine photographs of railroad floating equipment.
- Railroads' Exhibit No. 4. Employee Classification., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Railroads' Exhibit No. 8. Wages., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Railroads' Exhibit No. 13. Wage and Earnings Data., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Railroads' Exhibit No. 15. Vacation and Holiday Proposals., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Railroads' Exhibit No. 16. 1960 Agreement. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  August 19 1960.
- Railroads' Exhibit No. 17. Retirement, Unemployment and Sickness Benefits., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Railroads' Exhibit No. 19. General Wage Increases., 1937-1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Railroads' Exhibit No. 20. Employment Cost Increases., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Railroads' Exhibit No. 22. Agreements., 1936-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)